MICHAEL B. TERKHORN

(317) 690-3555 | miketerkhorn@gmail.com

Sales Professional of 15 years with strengths in account management and relationship sales. Background in working with companies of all sizes and building relationships with prospective buyers in multiple industries. Passionate about learning new products and services and demonstrating the advantages and benefits to customers.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Monarch Beverage Co. Inc., Indianapolis, IN

January 2011 - Present

Beer and wine wholesaler servicing much of the state of Indiana.

Sales Representative

- Built and managed relationships with customers in four unique retail channels.
- Internal promotions resulting in 5 territory advancements in 9 years.
- Grew market share with existing customer base year over year.
- Cultivated relationships to grow sales and market share within defined territories year after year.
- Successfully executing sales strategies within 5 different territories across multiple sales divisions.
- Influenced buying strategy to key shift in high volume packages leading to higher gross margins.
- Independently provided week to week tracking solutions to state's top buyer enabling buying decisions.

G&K Services, Indianapolis, IN

March 2010 - January 2011

Provides branded uniforms and facility services for rent or purchase.

Territory Sales Representative

- Established a sales territory using cold calling and referral prospecting.
- Grew business month over month for first 6 months.
- Created and maintained relationships with businesses of all types and sizes.

Weichert Realtors, Indianapolis, IN

January 2009 – March 2010

Residential Realtor

• Developed a network of relationships and prospects in the Indianapolis real estate market.

Ameritox Ltd, Indianapolis, IN

November 2006 – November 2008

Diagnostic Laboratory providing physicians with urine drug monitoring and reporting.

Senior Sales Representative, Field Operations Representative

- Developed and cultivated relationships with clinical staff in a Midwest territory of anesthesiologists, physiatrists and family practices.
- Selected to be a Field Based Trainer for the Midwest region.

- Grew territory from the ground up establishing a strong client base with strong same store sales numbers in the Indianapolis market.
- Established a paradigm shift for many physicians by illustrating the benefits of a product previously not available.
- Implemented products and services in more than 60 new accounts.
- Averaged of 108% to goal and 100% same store sales over 15 months.
- Successfully leveraged large geographic territory utilizing strong time and territory management skills.

ExecuTrain of Indianapolis, Indianapolis, IN

March 2004 - November 2006

Training center providing on-site classroom training on computer and soft skills.

Sales Manager, Educational Services Coordinator/Account Executive

- Established and managed relationships with over 500 companies ranging from 1 to 4,000 employees.
- Accountable for overall company sales on a monthly basis.
- Forecasted and established sales goals and pipeline growth.
- Collaborated on process of selecting, hiring and training of new sales representatives.
- Top in company sales for 2005, consisting of 36% of overall company sales.
- Won back 10 large accounts from main competitor in marketplace.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Management, Indiana University